Finding Aid for the Alfred H. Bartles Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- DETAILED CONTAINER LIST
  - Series E: Miscellaneous Materials
    - Miscellaneous—Personal (Box 48)
      - Documents/Contracts, Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 1)
        Metropolitan Government of Nashville & Davidson County, Office of Vital Records—Death certificate, 2006
      - Résumés/Curricula vitæ (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Biographies/Autobiographies (Box 48, Folder 3)
        Note: Related autobiographical materials in Box 19.
      - Diplomas/Certificates (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Documents/Records/Other—Paul L.H. Bartles, (1891-1935) (Box 48, Folder 5)
        Materials related to Paul L.H. Bartles, Alfred’s father
        - Writings/Miscellaneous Records (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Teachings of a Master of the Italian School (of Cello Playing) / Francesco Tulli, recorded by his student, Alfred H. Bartles, Jul. 31, 1967 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - The Pick Ups / by Alfred H. Bartles (Box 48, Folder 7)
        Note: These texts are related to the pedagogical work held in Box 13
      - Other writings/Fragments (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Composition Inventories (Box 48, Folder 9)
        - Music by Others (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Music by Others, edited by Alfred H. Bartles (Box 10)
        Bach, J.S. Ricercar a 6 from the Musical Offering. Arranged by John Lewis for mixed voices (S.A.T.B.), piano, string bass and drums. New York, N.Y.: MJQ Music, ©1971
        Purcell, Henry. Dido’s Lament. Adapted by John Lewis for mixed voices (S.A.T.B.), piano, string bass, and drums. New York, N.Y.: MJQ Music, ©1971
        - Diary Notebooks (Box 48, Folder 10)
          Note: One diary notebook is housed among the sketchbooks in Box 19 due to size and additional content
      - Diary notebooks, Teaching and otherwise—ca., 1962-1964 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Diary notebooks, Teaching and otherwise—ca., 1969-1970 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous—Personal (Box 49)
      - Diary notebooks, Teaching and otherwise—ca., 1977 (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Gradebooks (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Gradebooks, Personal (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Gradebooks, as Instructor, 1970-1974 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Gradebooks, as Instructor, 1974-1979 (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - Records/Notes, Various (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Students of the Rudolf Steiner School, N.Y.C. (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Students of the Rudolf Steiner School, N.Y.C. (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Students of the Rudolf Steiner School, N.Y.C. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Students of the Rudolf Steiner School, N.Y.C. (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous—Personal (Box 50)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Former cello students, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Former cello students, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Former cello students, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Former cello students, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Records, Miscellaneous—Sewanee (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Lecture notes, etc.—Schiller College (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Lecture notes, etc.—Schiller College (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Lecture notes, etc.—Schiller College (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Teaching notes, etc.—Theory/Harmony Courses, ca., 1974-1980 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Teaching notes, etc.—Theory/Harmony Courses, ca., 1974-1980 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Teaching notes, etc.—Theory/Harmony Courses, ca., 1974-1980 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Teaching notes, etc.—Theory/Harmony Courses, ca., 1974-1980 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Teaching notes, etc.—Theory/Harmony Courses, ca., 1974-1980 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous—Personal/Event Programs (Box 51)
      - Notebook—Improved Music Study for Beginners, 1937-1942 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Notebook—Ohio University, 1953-1954 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Notes—Eurythmeum (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Notes—Eurythmeum (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Itineraries, Miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Itineraries, Miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 5)
        - Event Programs (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Event programs, Undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Event programs, 1941-1959 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Event programs, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Event Programs (Box 52)
      - Event programs, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Event programs, 1962-1969 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Event programs, 1970-1974 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Event programs, 1975-1979 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Event programs, 1980-1984 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Event programs, 1985-1989 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Event programs, 1990-1999 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Event Programs/Writings by Others (Box 53)
      - Event programs, 2000-2004 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Event programs, 2005-2013 (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - Writings by Others (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Independent Texts (Box 53, Folder 3)
        One Branch of the Woodses. Compiled by Rev. Edgar Woods. Charlottesville, Va.: [s.n.], 1894
        Daniels, Bill. Nashville with Alf [n.d.]
        [Document describing activities of Alfred H. Bartles and Bill Daniels heavily referencing past correspondence]
        Special Diet I. Compiled by W. Kaelin and R. Leroi, [n.d.]
        Leroi, A. “Rudolf Steiner’s Contribution to the Understanding and Treatment of Cancer.” Translation from Die Drei no. 1 (Jan. 1961)
        Bälan, George. “Introduction aux problems esthétiques de la musique moderne.” Analele Universitäpi Bucuresti. Seria Stiinfe Sociale Estética, 1968
      - Independent Texts (Box 53, Folder 4)
        Bühler, W. and R. Leroi. “Cancer as a Disease: Causes, Prevention and Control.” Trans. Heide Ehrenberger. Soziale Hygiene 19, 1969, photocopy of typescript
        Leroi, Rita. “Iscador Treatment of Carcinoma.” Reprinted from The British Homoeopathic Journal v. 61, no. 23 (Jul. 1972)
        Bälan, George. “Le concept d’antimusique et la crise de la société contemporaine.” Reprint from Proceedings of the Sixth International Congress of Aesthetics at Uppsala 1968. Acta universitatis Upsaliensis series Figura, n. s., vol. 10,1972
        Institute of American Music of the University of Rochester. American Composers’ Concerts and Festivals of American Music 1925-1971, Cumulative Repertoire. Rochester, New York: Institute of American Music, 1972
      - Independent Texts (Box 53, Folder 5)
        50 Jahre Eurythmeum Stuttgart, 1923-1973 (various authors)
        Schiller College Bonnigheim 1972/73, college yearbook
      - Independent Texts (Box 53, Folder 6)
        Lieberman, Jean Crowell. Poems. [S.I.]: [s.n.], [n.d.]
        Elliott, Francis E. “The Cultural Role of Music in Education in Our Technological Age.” Tennessee Musician, May 1977: p. 8, photocopy
        Perle, George. “The Secret Programme of the Lyric Suite.” [N.d.]:[s.n.], Aug.-Sept. 1977, in 3 sections, photocopy
        Davis, Louise. “Visiting ‘Grandma’ at the Hermitage.” The Tennessean, Dec. 1977: p. 32-34, photocopy
        Elliott, Francis. “String Playing in the Music of Bach and Handel.” Tennessee Musician, May 1985, p. 6
        Gower, Dona S. “Hero, Healer, and Martyr: Greek Paradigms of the Teacher.” Parabola, Spring 1989, p. 44-50, photocopy
        Young, Jerry A. [Review for T.U.B.A. Journal], 2003
        Computer-printed copy of review of the recording Tennessee Tech Pride
      - Newsletters/Journal issues, 1965-1995 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Newsletters/Journal issues, 1997-2007 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Brochures, Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings/Other (Box 54)
      Note: Many newspaper clippings originally enclosed with correspondence have been retained within Series D.
      - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1951-1954 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1955-1959 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1965 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1972-1974 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1985 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1986-1991 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1992-2006 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous—Receipts, Tickets, Lists, Postcards, Other (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Photographs (Box 55)
      Note: Additional photos can be found in Box 56. Photographs originally enclosed with correspondence have been retained within Series D.
      - Photographs—Miscellaneous (Box 55)
        Includes one envelope of negatives
      - Photographs—ca. to 1935, Paul Bartles (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Photographs—ca., 1935-1948 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Photographs—ca., 1948-1952 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Photographs—Martha Smith Bartles—ca. to 1952 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Photographs—ca., 1952-1953 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Photographs—ca., 1954 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Photographs—ca., 1955-1959 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Photographs—ca., 1960 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Photographs—ca., 1961-1963 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Photographs—ca., 1963 (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Photographs—ca., 1964 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Photographs—ca., 1965-1966 (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - Photographs—ca., 1967-1968 (Box 55, Folder 14)
      - Photographs—ca., 1969 (Box 55, Folder 15)
      - Photographs—ca., 1970 (Box 55, Folder 16)
      - Photographs—ca., 1971-1972 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous—Personal/Event Programs (Box 55A)
      - Photographs—ca., 1973-1979 (Box 55A, Folder 1)
      - Photographs—ca., 1980-1982 (Box 55A, Folder 2)
      - Photographs—ca., 1983 (Box 55A, Folder 3)
      - Photographs—ca., 1984 (Box 55A, Folder 4)
      - Photographs—ca., 1985-1986 (Box 55A, Folder 5)
      - Photographs—ca., 1987-1989 (Box 55A, Folder 6)
      - Photographs—ca., 1990 (Box 55A, Folder 7)
      - Photographs—ca., 1991-1994 (Box 55A, Folder 8)
      - Photographs—ca., 1995-1996 (Box 55A, Folder 9)
      - Photographs—ca., 1997-1999 (Box 55A, Folder 10)
      - Photographs—ca., 2000-2006 (Box 55A, Folder 11)
      - Photographs—Compilations, Booklets (Box 55A, Folder 12)
    - Photographs (Box 55B)
      - Photographs—Compilations, Booklets (Box 55B, Folder 1)
      - Photographs—Framed (Box 55B, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbooks/Other miscellaneous (Box 55B)
      - [Guest book from the 2015 Bartles Memorial Concert and concert program] (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - [Commemorative poster on the event of Bartles’s retirement in 1996] (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - “Zur Erinnerung an die gemeinsamen 13 Jahre und mit den besten Geburtstagswünschen für meinen lieben Cellolehrer A.H.B. von Ihrer Sabine Winkler”, 1985: spiral-bound booklet from former student Sabine Winkler containing scales and non-pedagogical color illustrations (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - [Scrapbookfrom Bartles’s cello studio in Germany], ca., 1996 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - [Scrapbook compiled on the event of Alfred and Martha Bartles’ 50th wedding anniversary], 2004 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Vault Oversize: Miscellaneous—Personal/Event Programs (Box 56)
      - Alfred H. Bartles Memorial Concert Poster, Dec. 6, 2015, Blair School of Music (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - “Für Herrn Bartles”, Jan. 1996: oversize card to Bartles from student Julia Schweizer (Box 56, Folder 2)